Preliminary Inventory of the Albert V. Baez Papers, 1955-2004 85011
Hoover Institution Archives
Albert V. Baez Papers,
1955-2004
85011
Hoover Institution Archives
51 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (22.6 linear feet)
Correspondence, minutes, reports, studies, memoranda, and printed matter, relating to international efforts to promote conservation and public awareness regarding conservation.
Baez, Albert V.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1985.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Abbreviations
IUCN International Union for Conservation of Nature and Natural Resources
CE Commission on Education of the IUCN
International Union for Conservation of Nature and Natural Resources.; Conservation of natural resources--Study and teaching.; Education.; Environmental policy.; International cooperation.; Science--International cooperation.
- Hoffmann, Alfred - correspondence, 1979-80 (Box 1)
- Munro, David A. - correspondence, 1979-80
- General correspondence, 1979-80
- Dajani, Naseeb - correspondence, 1979-80
- correspondence, 1980
  - A-F
  - G-T (Box 2)
  - U-Z (Box 3)
- IUCN Council, 1979-80
- IUCN Programme Planning Advisory Group, 1979-80
- Outgoing letters, 1981 (Box 4)
- correspondence, 1981
  - A-B
  - Boulton, Mark
  - Diamond, Judy
  - C-L (Box 5)
  - Henning, Daniel H.
  - Headlands Foundation
  - Herz, Michael J.
  - M-Z (Box 6)
  - Maldague, Michel
  - Meeker, Joseph W.
  - Stapp, William B.
- IUCN 15th general assembly, Christchurch, New Zealand, including resolutions and CE report, 1981 (Box 7)
- New Zealand brochures and information
- IUCN 10th Council meeting, Christchurch, 1981
- IUCN Programme Planning Advisory Group meeting, Gland, Switzerland, 1981
- IUCN 9th Council meeting, Gland, 1981
- IUCN 9th Council meeting, Gland, 1981 (Box 8)
- IUCN Bureau meetings, 1979-80
- United Nations Environment Programme Governing Council - statement by Lee M. Talbot, 1981
- CE report, 1980
- IUCN 14th Bureau meeting, London, 1982
- IUCN Programme Planning Advisory Group meeting, Nyon, Switzerland, 1982
- IUCN 13th Bureau meeting, Gland, 1982
- International Conference on Education and the Environment, Hamilton, Ontario, - documents including speech preparation, 1982
- International Conference on Education and the Environment, Hamilton, Ontario, - correspondence and source material, 1982 (Box 9)
- Outgoing letters, 1982
- correspondence - CE members, 1982
  - A-G
  - H-Z (Box 10)
- 1982 miscellaneous correspondence - A-Z (Box 11)
- IUCN Commission on National Parks and Protected Areas, 1979-82
- IUCN Commission on Environmental Policy, Law and Administration, 1980-82
- IUCN Commission on Ecology, 1979-82 (Box 12)
- IUCN Commission on Environmental Planning, 1979-82
- IUCN Species Survival Commission, 1979-82
- Marton-Lefevre, Julia - correspondence, 1979-84
- IUCN Conservation Plan, comments on, 1983
- correspondence - CE members, 1983 (Box 13)
  - A-S
  - Schwarzschild, Bert (Box 14)
  - Smyth, J. C.
  - T-Z
- miscellaneous correspondence - A-Z, 1983
- Outgoing letters, 1983 (Box 15)
- Replies to request re continuation of membership, 1984
- CE - lists of members
- IUCN Task Force Review Paper, 1979-80 (Box 16)
- CE background information
- Curricula vitae
  - D-Z
  - A-C (Box 17)
- United Nations Environment Programme project, 1981-83
- CE Steering Committee meeting, Malvern, England, 1983
- CE Steering Committee meeting, Berne, 1980
- CE Meetings, Christchurch, 1981
- CE Steering Committee meeting, Greenbrae, California, - preparatory documents and notes, 1981
- CE Steering Committee meeting, Greenbrae, 1982
- CE Steering Committee - members and program
- Dajani, Naseeb - correspondence
  - 1983
  - 1981-84 (Box 18)
- Proposed newsletter for CE
- IUCN regional and national committees
  - General
  - United States
  - Mexico
  - Ireland (Box 19)
  - East Europe
  - Wider Caribbean Region
  - Costa Rica
  - North American Region
  - Oman
  - Australia
  - Northwest Europe
  - North Atlanic U.S.
  - Canada
  - Britain
  - India
  - Nepal (Box 20)
- Miller, Kenton R. - correspondence, 1983-84
- Talbot, Lee M. - correspondence, 1980-82
- Telegrams and Telex messages
- Funding sources
- IUCN/World Wildlife Fund projects
  - General
  - Projects on tropical forests and primates
  - Indonesian project
  - Wetlands project
  - Plants project (Box 21)
- Gorska, Jadwiga - correspondence, 1983-1984
- McNeely, Jeffrey A. - correspondence, 1983-84
- Zentilli, Bernardo - correspondence, 1983-84
- Alan, Donald - correspondence, 1983-84
- Lamb, Robert W. - correspondence, 1984
- Kassas, Mohamed - correspondence, 1980-83
- Duke, William J. Y. - correspondence, 1980-83
- Sand, Peter H. - correspondence, 1982-83
- Staff correspondence, 1979
- Boote, Robert E. - correspondence, 1982
- Scriabine, Raisa - press releases, 1981-83
- Phillips, Adrian - correspondence, 1980-81 (Box 22)
- Cockerell, Mike - correspondence, 1981-84
- Suwald, Stephan - correspondence, 1982
- Mence, A. J. - correspondence, 1979-82
- World Conservation Strategy - report by Lee M. Talbot, 1981
- Scott, Sir Peter - correspondence, 1981-84
- Blum, Abraham - correspondence, 1981
- United Nations Environment Programme project for environmental administration training handbook, 1983
- United Nations Environment Programme projects - education for conservation, 1982-84
- Project on environmental education in India
- Gandhi, Indira - correspondence (photocopies), 1981-83
- IUCN Bulletin - drafts of articles
- Museums
- Project proposals, miscellaneous
- Tropical rain forests, including Natural Resources Defense Council correspondence, 1980-82
- Incremental materials (Box 23-52)
  Scope and Contents note
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.
- Motion picture film
  - "Introduction to Holography (Color)" 16mm film, 1972 (Box 52)
  - "Learning About Light (Color)" 16mm film, 1972 (Box 52)